Adeoluwa Adelekan



dee.adelekan@gmail.com

(301)-312-4904

Objective: I am a highly motivated Software Developer with 2+ years of experience building and deploying web applications using modern frameworks (Angular, React, MEAN Stack). With the proven abilities to collaborate effectively in an Agile team environment and leverage a multitude of development tools, I am seeking a challenging role to contribute my expertise and further develop skills in software development.

Education

Towson University - B.Sc., Computer Science

May 2023

Santa Fe College - Associate in Arts, Computer Science

December 2019

Certifications

AWS Certified Developer - Associate

June 2024

Experience

Alpha Omega Integration (June 2022 - June 2023)

Applications Developer

- Developed and deployed interactive web forms using Angular and TypeScript, bringing project completion to about
 75%
- Implemented features such as WebSocket connections for group connectivity, animations for improved UI/UX, and CSS styling to match the theme of the company's primary website.
- Collaborated with a team of professionals and engaged in Agile Sprint planning, review, and execution.
- Used Jira to capture customer requirements and transform them into a backlog of user stories.
- Gained experience developing AWS resources on a serverless backend using tools such as Lambda, API Gateway, Cognito, CloudFormation.
- DevOps experience using a CI/CD pipeline (AWS CodeBuild & Pipeline) to test and deploy builds to production.
- Created and managed pull requests across multiple branches on GitHub
- Experience with development toolchain tools such as Cypress, Cucumber
- Experience in E2E testing and other scripting/programming languages (Nodejs, HTML, CSS, Gherkin)
- Documented some software procedures on Confluence.

Awo Title, LLC (June 2021 - June 2022)

Full-Stack Developer

- Used JavaScript, Typescript, and HTML with MEAN stack to develop and maintain the company's web application.
- Engaged in multiple Sprints for incremental improvement of the web application through implemented features.
- Helped implement notification system and other web application features that enhanced the internal title handling and refinancing process, saving the company over \$20,000 in fees and speeding up company operations.
- Experience with Agile team collaboration using Microsoft Azure's suite of tools.
- Investigated bugs that appeared.
- Wrote API documentation for most endpoints of the web application, listing possible responses, requested data, and etc. (1000+ lines)

Retail Merchandising Services (December 2020 - November 2021)

Merch Representative

- Serviced Target locations around Maryland.
- Partnered with retailers such as L'Oréal and their subsidiaries to organize and keep an accurate inventory of their products in stores.
- Partnered with other vendors to complete a wide variety of projects that include auditing, zoning, counting, and setting items in Target and other stores.

Technical Skills

- C++, JavaScript/TS, Python, HTML, Java, SASS, Swift, React, Rust
- Retail/Merchandising
- E2E Testing and QA
- Serverless Computing
- Agile Development
- Cloud Platforms: AWS, Azure

Soft Skills

- Excellent communication
- Interpersonal skills
- Critical thinking
- Collaboration
- Time Management